Episode 9
第 9 集
Madam, he has arrived.
夫人，他来了。
Hello, madam.
你好女士。
I am currently underemployed.
我目前就业不足。
Don't mind what I said before.
别介意我之前说的话。
There might be a conflict with Jong Ye-ran...
可能会和钟艺兰发生冲突……
But I still...
但我还是...
Daughter of the Hwa family...
华家的女儿……
And my father is an assistant here.
我父亲是这里的助理。
If you keep working here...
如果你继续在这里工作...
You will profit.
你将会获利。
Because I took care of my wife...
因为我照顾我的妻​​子...
Madam, you are my only master.
夫人，您是我唯一的主人。
good!
好的！
I said there was hope...
我说还有希望...
And I was right.
我是对的。
Please let me know if you need help.
如果您需要帮助，请告诉我。
There is a lot for you to do...
有很多事情等着你去做...
now.
现在。
- Kuiju - Yes!
- 奎巨 - 是的！
help.
帮助。
I'm going.
我要去。
Go ahead and try it.
继续尝试。
Why do you look at me like that?
你为什么这样看着我？
I heard.
我听说。
What did you hear?
你听到了什么？
Just don't push...
只是别推...
It's the cost of food and clothes, ma'am.
这是食物和衣服 的费用，女士。
As well as moving all employees...
以及移动所有员工...
A person who cleans his area.
清洁他的区域的人。
Chief of security, don't be stupid.
保安队长， 别傻了。
I don't dare...
我不敢...
Wants to cut down on his expenses.
想减少他的开支。
This is your command.
这是你的命令。
Did you tell them to move all the employees?
你让他们把所有员工都搬走吗？
Don't think I don't know...
别以为我不知道...
He never gave any such instructions.
他 从未发出过任何此类指示。
As a result, women...
结果， 女性...
Everyone is busy.
每个人都很忙。
It's not my fault.
这不是我的错。
Even without giving these instructions...
即使没有给出这些指示...
subordinates and subordinates...
下属 和下属...
I came here to ask for a change.
我来这里是为了要求改变。
It's difficult to please everyone.
很难让所有人都满意。
I have no choice but to follow their will.
我 别无选择，只能遵从他们的意愿。
After all, you are not against it.
毕竟你并不反对。
Don't use him as an excuse.
别拿他当借口。
You misunderstood.
你误会了。
I wouldn't dare.
我不敢。
You can cut costs , but don't overdo it.
你可以削减成本 ，但不要过度。
Follow the rules.
按照规则。
If you know this, you take responsibility.
如果你知道这一点，你就承担责任。
But if you listen...
但如果你听...
You treat women rudely...
你 对待女人很粗鲁...
I won't be rude to you.
我不会对你无礼。
Remember, I'm in charge of security...
请记住，我 负责安全...
In this area.
在这个区域。
great.
伟大的。
approval.
赞同。
For those who want to go...
对于那些想去的人...
No need to move again.
无需再次移动。
We do not need to imprison unfaithful people .
我们不需要监禁不忠的人 。
of.
的。
Don't forget...
别忘了...
To command your people.
来指挥你的人民。
great.
伟大的。
am...
是...
Is he really serious?
他真的是认真的吗？
I'm ready, ma'am.
我准备好了，女士。
Isn’t this kind of cool?
这不是很酷吗？
This isn't the first time...
这不是第一次...
I met that woman.
我遇见了那个女人。
Miss has just recovered.
小姐刚刚康复。
So a luxurious appearance will bring good luck.
所以奢华的外表 会带来好运。
great.
伟大的。
Is the cart ready?
购物车准备好了吗？
We don't need to get out...
我们不需要出去...
And it pays, right?
而且它是值得的，对吧？
I confirm.
我确定。
Madam, stop.
女士，停下来。
Your brother sent it to you, right?
你哥哥发给你的吧？
I told him many times...
我跟他说过很多次了...
But he doesn't want to hear it.
但他不想听。
He still buys me jewelry.
他仍然给我买珠宝。
All of this puts a strain on running.
所有这些都给跑步带来了压力。
Next time he sends more items...
下次他寄更多的东西时...
I can keep pushing.
我可以继续推动。
Please tell me I'm not interested in that.
请告诉我我对此不感兴趣。
This is no ordinary gem.
这不是普通的宝石。
Finally my brother learned something.
弟弟终于学到了东西。
He discovered something special.
他发现了一些特别的东西。
Madam, be careful.
女士，小心点。
This knife is small...
这把刀很小...
But it's very sharp.
但它非常锋利。
How sharp is it?
有多锋利？
Tell it to your brother...
告诉你哥哥吧...
I really like this.
我真的很喜欢这个。
I didn't mean to do that.
我不是有意这么做的。
wake up. Don't be too polite.
醒来。 别太客气了。
Tell me please...
请告诉我...
How do I make this into a bracelet again?
我怎样才能把它重新变成手镯呢？
This is very useful for self-defense.
这 对于自卫非常有用。
I have nothing...
我什么都没有...
You can watch it here.
你可以在这里观看。
I want to go to Jong Park...
我想去郑园...
We need a security guard.
我们需要一名保安。
Can you take me there?
你能带我去那里吗？
good.
好的。
Young boys are obedient.
小男孩很听话。
Miss, shouldn't you be there?
小姐， 你不应该在吗？
I was invited here.
我被邀请来到这里。
It's daytime now.
现在是白天。
I don't think anyone would dare...
我想没有人敢...
want to trap me
想困住我
are you okay. We will go alone.
你还好吗。 我们将独自前往。
Coincidentally, my daughter-in-law.
巧的是，我的儿媳妇。
What is my destiny?
我的命运是什么？
I want to see my mom by chance.
我想有机会见到我妈妈。
Let's go together.
咱们一起去吧。
Has your injury healed?
你的伤痊愈了吗？
The length of a day at Jong Residence...
Jong Residence 一天的长度...
I didn't have time to ask more...
我没时间问更多...
Because my senior wants to see it.
因为我的前辈想看。
At that time, you asked a detailed question ...
当时你问了一个很详细的问题 ...
And I'm fine now.
我现在很好。
I think you're still angry.
我想你还在生气。
You still think...
你还认为...
I've been testing you all this time?
我一直在考验你？
You must be joking.
你一定是在开玩笑。
I dare not think so.
我不敢这么想。
Don't you dare think that...
你敢不敢这么想……
But aren't you angry?
但你不生气吗？
To be clear...
需要明确的是...
I will never second-guess your actions again.
我再也不会怀疑你的行为了。
can you forgive me
你能原谅我吗
why?
为什么？
Are you talking to me?
你在跟我讲话吗？
Who else?
还有谁？
All your thoughts must have meaning.
你所有的想法都 必须有意义。
So there’s no guessing, right?
所以没有猜测，对吧？
Just forget it. There will be times like that.
把它忘了吧。 会有这样的时候。
I remembered what you said last time...
我记得上次你说的话...
And I thought that was very reasonable.
我认为这是非常合理的。
Sekali Ragi.
Sekali Ragi。
Didn’t you promise not to make any more guesses ?
你不是答应过不再做任何猜测吗 ？
Forgive me for what I didn't know...
请原谅我不知道的事...
But can you tell what's wrong with me?
但 你能告诉我我出了什么问题吗？
I said I would stop making assumptions about you.
我 说过我不会再对你做出假设。
So you don't need to be too careful .
所以你不需要太小心 。
I am a fool If I believe you
我是个傻瓜 如果我相信你
You said that a person lives only once.
你说一个人的生命只有一次。
Therefore, it is not worth risking your life for.
因此，不值得冒生命危险。
We'll have to think about this in the future.
我们将来必须考虑这个问题。
You're threatening my life?
你在威胁我的生命吗？
I mean, you...
我是说你...
Hello, madam.
你好女士。
Please sit next to me.
请坐在我旁边。
Yes ma'am.
是的女士。
You are so bad.
你是如此糟糕。
Yelan is skilled in martial arts.
夜阑武功高强。
There is no need to protect him from arrows.
没有必要保护他免受箭矢的伤害。
It hurts for a long time...
疼了好久...
And make me worry about you...
还让我担心你...
At this age.
在这个年纪。
The lady is right.
这位女士是对的。
I feel really bad and am in too much of a hurry.
我感觉很糟糕而且 太着急了。
Thank you for your consideration.
谢谢您的考虑。
I won't do it again.
我不会再这样做了。
Look how skinny you are.
看看你有多瘦。
I used to think you were so weak.
我曾经以为你很弱。
Now you are thin.
现在你瘦了。
How do you want to give birth?
你想怎样分娩？
membrane.
膜。
Mom is picky.
妈妈很挑剔。
I have been here for a long time.
我已经在这里很久了。
But I feel like my mom can't see me.
但我感觉妈妈看不见我。
How dare you say that?
你怎么敢这么说？
You are not married yet.
你还没有结婚。
Then Yellen would be better...
那么耶伦会更好...
To have grandchildren.
要有孙子。
I heard they boil noodles...
听说他们煮面条...
For his birthday.
为了他的生日。
I just cook as usual.
我只是像往常一样做饭。
Intention matters.
意图很重要。
Spoiled little girls like you are rare.
像你这样被宠坏的小女孩很少见。
I want to go into the kitchen...
我想进厨房...
And please cook noodles for him.
还请他煮面条。
You've been sick for a long time...
你已经病了很久了...
But why aren't you saying anything to me ?
但你为什么不跟我说话 ？
I am really worried...
我真的很担心...
Almost sent a doctor .
差点就派出医生了 。
Mom, I heard you were in a coma for 5 days...
妈妈，听说你昏迷了五天了……
And I am very worried.
我很担心。
So he told me to bring Dr. Wu here.
所以他 让我带吴医生过来。
Please forgive. That won't happen next time.
请原谅。 下次就不会这样了。
Next time?
下次？
Don't you think I've lived too long ?
你不觉得我活得太久了 吗？
I said wrong. Please forgive.
我说错了。 请原谅。
Madam, don't be angry.
女士，您别生气。
I shouldn't be angry.
我不应该生气。
ma'am.
女士。
I will remember everything you told me.
我 会记住你告诉我的一切。
How are you.
你好吗。
Your wife is the same.
你的妻子也是一样。
It's late, so we have to go now.
时间已经很晚了， 我们得走了。
I need to rest early.
我需要早点休息。
I will definitely visit next time .
下次我一定会去的。
OK. Be careful on your way.
好的。 路上要小心。
great.
伟大的。
Mom, it's late.
妈妈，很晚了。
So I won't bother you any more.
所以我不会再打扰你了。
go away.
离开。
Sister-in-law.
嫂子。
Hua Chen.
华晨.
What are you doing
你在干什么
It is not okay for men and women to touch each other.
男人和女人之间不可以互相接触。
Needless to say, I am your sister-in-law.
不用说，我是你嫂子。
Are you trying to do something bad to me?
你是想对我做坏事吗？
I called you a few times ago.
我之前给你打过几次电话。
But you pretend not to hear it.
但你假装没听见。
Why are you blaming me now ?
你为什么现在怪罪我 ？
Did you call me?
你给我打电话了吗？
It reminds me of Tuan Yelan.
这让我想起了团也兰。
So I hurried home but didn't hear anything.
于是我赶紧回家，但 什么也没听到。
Didn't you file your divorce papers a few days ago?
你不是前几天递交了离婚文件吗？
Why are you still using him as an excuse?
为什么还拿他当借口？
The teacher is very busy.
老师很忙。
Don't disturb me...
别打扰我...
To someone else's family problems.
为了别人的家庭问题。
What's going on today?
今天发生什么事了？
Like someone made you angry .
就像有人惹你生气了 。
Sir, if you have nothing more to say...
先生，如果您没什么可说的了……
i want to go now
现在我要走了
Let me finish my speech, shall we ?
让我结束我的演讲，好吗 ？
What I wanted to say earlier is...
我之前想说的是...
Cherishing your life is...
珍惜生命就是...
If you truly want me to cherish my life...
如果你真的 想让我珍惜我的生命...
You shouldn't bother me here .
你不应该在这里打扰我 。
There are a lot of people in Zong Park.
宗公园里人很多。
Have you ever thought...
你有没有想过...
My condition...
我的情况...
When others see us?
当别人看到我们的时候？
No one dares talk about us.
没有人敢 谈论我们。
No one will say anything about you.
没有人 会说任何关于你的事情。
But what about me?
但我呢？
I am no longer loved by Tuan Yelan.
我不再被团夜兰爱了。
My father is getting older too.
我的父亲也渐渐老了。
My brother got nothing.
我的兄弟什么也没有得到。
As a woman, I feel lonely and helpless...
作为一个女人， 我感到孤独和无助......
And of course...
而且当然...
You won't understand my struggles.
你不会理解我的挣扎。
The way you describe your situation is ...
你描述你的情况的方式是 ......
Do you still think I'm testing you ?
你还觉得我在考验你 吗？
Just forget it.
把它忘了吧。
Madam, why are you so brave today?
夫人， 今天怎么这么勇敢？
He is our master.
他是我们的主人。
Of course I know.
我当然知道。
Because that person is our master...
因为那个人是我们的主人……
If you say that, he will know now...
如果你这么说， 他现在就知道了……
He doesn't need to use me...
他不需要利用我...
To oppress my family.
来欺压我的家人。
Let's get out of here quickly.
我们快点离开这里吧。
why?
为什么？
I was angry that he was testing me.
我很生气他在考验我。
So my tone of voice was harsh.
所以我的语气很严厉。
Maybe when he realizes, he will punish me.
也许当他意识到时，他会惩罚我。
fast.
快速地。
This is new.
这是新的。
Lady, don't forget your father's instructions.
女士，请不要忘记父亲的嘱咐。
Don't interfere in other people's business.
不要干涉别人的事。
You don't need to remind me.
你不需要提醒我。
When I saw Qian today...
今天见到钱的时候...
He didn't care about Yellen.
他不关心耶伦。
Maybe you're still angry.
也许你还在生气。
then...
然后...
He will complain.
他会抱怨。
Look at the way I talk about Yellen today ...
看看我今天谈论耶伦的方式 ......
But he didn't want to talk about Yelan .
但他不想谈论夜阑 。
Would you like to meet Ms. Yellen?
您想见见耶伦女士吗？
It's unreasonable...
这是不合理的...
Yelan ignored Qian.
夜阑没有理睬谦。
But I am old.
但我老了。
They didn't ask me for help.
他们没有向我寻求帮助。
If I interfere in their business...
如果我 干涉他们的事...
I just harass them.
我 只是骚扰他们。
ma'am.
女士。
Tuan Yelan's parents died when he was young.
团夜兰的父母在他很小的时候就去世了。
Mr. and Mrs....
先生和夫人....
serve him...
为他服务...
From a young age, like your own child.
从小就像自己的孩子一样。
He won't think of you as a troublemaker.
他不会认为你是个麻烦制造者。
After all, as long as they are still husband and wife...
毕竟，只要他们 还是夫妻……
They will be together again.
他们会再次在一起。
Qian is a smart girl...
茜是个聪明的女孩...
but...
但...
sadly.
可悲的是。
Mom, it's late.
妈妈，很晚了。
So I won't bother you any more.
所以我不会再打扰你了。
ma'am.
女士。
why?
为什么？
naught.
什么也没有。
Maybe I'm thinking too much.
也许是我想太多了。
I'm full. Clean the table.
我饱了。 清理桌子。
Okay, ma'am.
好的，女士。
ma'am.
女士。
I checked the store today...
今天去店里查了一下...
You can see all times and times, play chess, and write utensils...
可以看古今中外， 下棋，写器物……
The one Mr. Yelan gave me is very dusty.
夜阑先生给我的那本已经落满灰尘了。
Madame always makes fun of things like that without doing anything about it.
夫人总是拿这样的事情开玩笑，却没有采取任何行动。
What should I bring to the lady...
我应该给那位女士带什么...
Want to utilize your time?
想利用你的时间吗？
Qianzhi.
Qianzhi.
How do you think I will treat Jong Ye-ran...
你觉得我会怎样对待钟艺兰……
Before I get married?
在我结婚之前？
are you okay. You can answer freely.
你还好吗。 你可以自由回答。
Madam, I love you so much, sir.
女士，我非常爱你，先生。
He likes chess.
他喜欢下棋。
So you learned how to play from many teachers .
所以你从很多老师那里学会了如何演奏 。
He likes listening to guqin's music.
他喜欢听古琴音乐。
So you do everything to master it.
所以你 会尽一切努力来掌握它。
He appreciates beautiful handwriting.
他欣赏漂亮的书法。
So I still want to practice...
所以我还是想练习一下...
It doesn't matter whether the weather is hot or cold.
天气是热还是冷并不重要。
If you praise...
如果你夸...
Woman's drawing skills...
女人的绘画技巧...
Your wife is going to visit her...
你的妻子要去探望她...
meet...
见面...
And learn from him.
并向他学习。
great.
伟大的。
I never learned anything like that...
我从来没有学过这样的东西......
Because I like it.
因为我喜欢它。
So now I don't want to touch it anymore.
所以现在 我不想再碰它了。
Maybe you're a little angry.
也许你有点生气。
Do you want to apologize to that person?
你想向那个人道歉吗？
I hope he gets angry...
希望他生气...
And please remember my mistakes.
并且请记住我的错误。
I hope...
我希望...
He divorced me...
他和我离婚了...
So there's no need to think...
所以没必要想...
How do I force him?
我怎么强迫他？
What did you say?
你说什么？
ma'am.
女士。
Hua Residence's variety has arrived.
华府的品种到了。
And Maid Hua said she asked...
而花姑娘说她问过……
The lady is coming tomorrow.
小姐明天就来。
I have to go there.
我必须去那里。
Kian.
基安.
Qian, do you like the jewelry you sent me?
钱，你送我的首饰你喜欢吗？
of.
的。
So why not use it?
那么为什么不使用它呢？
Jewelry my brother bought me...
哥哥给我买的首饰
All of them are unique and beautiful.
它们都是独特而美丽的。
Matches your beauty...
很符合你的美貌...
Then you will surpass others.
那么你就会超越别人。
The emerald my brother bought me ...
哥哥给我买的翡翠 ...
i know. Look at.
我知道。看着。
This is from my brother. I wear it.
这是我哥哥送来的。 我穿着它。
Brother, can I give you this bracelet?
兄弟，我可以给你这个手链吗？
Calm down and talk to him.
冷静下来和他谈谈。
don't worry.
不用担心。
do not be angry.
别生气。
nurse.
护士。
membrane.
膜。
Mom son...
妈妈儿子...
I haven't seen you for a long time.
我已经很久没见到你了。
Why do you look thin?
为什么你看起来很瘦？
Did your master treat you badly?
你的主人对你不好吗？
Just talk.
只是说说。
I was wrong about that.
我错了。
A cruel and heartless man.
一个残忍 而无情的人。
Honey, please let me sit down first.
亲爱的，请让我先坐下。
sit down.
坐下。
Kian.
基安.
Was it cured?
治愈了吗？
I like it.
我喜欢。
I heard...
我听说...
Are you asking for a divorce?
你要求离婚吗？
- yes. - Why did you do that?
- 是的。 - 你为什么这么做？
You are no longer a slave.
你不再是奴隶了。
But you are still stubborn.
但你依然固执。
Why is my father angry at me without asking why?
为什么我的父亲 不问原因就生我的气？
Why else?
还有什么原因呢？
Because daddy spoils you so much.
因为爸爸太宠你了。
- Honey... - That's why you're so stubborn.
- 亲爱的... - 这就是为什么你这么固执。
to!
到！
Qian is still young.
钱还年轻。
Be patient with him.
对他要有耐心。
drinking water.
饮用水。
Drink water and stay calm.
喝水并保持冷静。
Kian.
基安.
This time Tuan Yelan made a mistake.
这一次团夜兰 犯了一个错误。
But you really want to marry that person.
但你真的 很想嫁给那个人。
right?
正确的？
Why are you still stubborn?
为什么你还是那么固执？
The secret to maintaining a marriage is ...
维持婚姻的秘诀是 ……
If you want to stay here for a while...
如果你想在这里停留一段时间...
Mom and Dad get scolded too...
爸爸妈妈也被骂了
Without asking why.
不问为什么。
Now it's the same.
现在也一样了。
Mom and Dad think of me as a child...
爸爸妈妈 都把我当小孩子看...
Or as the wife of a servant?
还是作为仆人的妻子？
It has to be first.
它必须是第一。
My sister thinks it's okay to divorce.
姐姐觉得 离婚也可以。
It's so beautiful...
这个很漂亮...
And there are many people like you.
像你这样的人还有很多。
You shouldn't stay there to be treated badly.
你不应该留在那里受到虐待。
shut up.
住口。
You are not qualified to speak!
你没有资格说话！
You just know how to play.
你只知道怎么玩。
If you have a stronger sense of responsibility...
如果你有更强的责任感...
Dad doesn't have to be hard...
爸爸不必那么辛苦...
For your family!
为了你的家人！
I never thought this would happen if my dad found out ...
没想到被我爸知道了 会发生这样的事……
Dad would be better off without a son!
爸爸没有儿子会更好！
to.
到。
Dad, tell me.
爸爸，告诉我。
What does your dad work hard for?
你爸爸辛苦工作是为了什么？
Dad wants to do that...
爸爸想要这么做...
Seize sole power in a servant's residence...
独揽仆人府中的权力……
Or do you want your family to be safe and happy?
还是希望家人平安幸福？
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
I never understood my father's feelings.
我一直无法理解父亲的感受。
So I want to listen to what Dad says.
所以我想听听爸爸怎么说。
What is the intention behind that question?
这个问题背后的意图是什么？
Because dad didn't answer...
因为爸爸没有回答...
Let's see.
让我们来看看。
I think that's what dad wants...
我想这就是爸爸想要的...
Aren't you in power in your servant's residence?
你不是在奴婢府里掌权吗？
Dad said he did everything for this family.
爸爸说他所做的一切都是为了这个家。
But the father did not teach his son well.
但父亲并没有教好儿子。
Look at his broken morals.
看看他的道德败坏。
Then I saw my son being abused...
然后我就看到我儿子被虐待了……
And scolded him for no reason.
还无缘无故地骂了他一顿。
For dad...
为了爸爸...
Am I just Jong Ye-ran’s wife?
我只是钟艺兰的妻子吗？
Qian, you can't talk to your father like that .
钱，你不能这样跟你爸爸说话。
Is there something wrong with what I said ?
难道我说的有什么问题 吗？
I broke up with Jong Ye-ran...
我和钟艺兰分手了...
And he allowed me to stay there without doing my duty.
他允许我留在那里而不履行我的职责。
Why can't I go there?
为什么我不能去那里？
Should I waste my life there?
我应该在那里浪费生命吗？
Don't you...
你难道...
Who wanted to marry him ?
谁想嫁给他 ？
Do you regret it now?
你现在后悔了吗？
of.
的。
I want to marry that person ...
我想嫁给那个人 ...
Pretending to be his childhood sweetheart .
假装是他的青梅竹马 。
I also drug her to marry me.
我还给她 下药，让她嫁给我。
What my father taught me...
我父亲教给我的...
Ever since I was little...
从小到大...
That I have to fight for what I want...
我必须为我想要的东西而奋斗……
No matter what happens.
不管发生什么。
I heard, I remember...
我听说过，我记得...
And do it.
并去做吧。
But I was young and naive.
但我当时还年轻、天真。
I don't know the difference between right and wrong.
我不知道对与错的区别。
I let my emotions control everything.
我让我的情绪 控制一切。
Dad knows too.
爸爸也知道。
But you don't know...
但你不知道...
What did I do wrong?
我做错了什么？
In my heart, my father always reigns supreme.
在我心里，父亲永远是至高无上的。
But why didn't my dad stop me?
但我爸爸为什么不阻止我呢？
While I pretend to be someone else?
当我 假装成别人的时候？
When I wanted to give medicine to Jong Ye-ran...
当我想给钟艺兰喂药时……
Why didn't you tell me...
你为什么不告诉我...
Women shouldn't be evil?
女人不应该作恶吗？
parents...
父母...
We need to fix the kids...
我们需要修复孩子们...
When they're on the wrong track, right?
当他们走错路的时候， 对吗？
Mom might be an ordinary woman...
妈妈可能是一个普通的女人...
With limited knowledge...
由于知识有限...
But dad...
但爸爸...
Won't you teach us what is right and what is wrong?
你不教教我们什么是对的，什么是错的吗？
nurse.
护士。
I don't think Dad will care right now...
我想爸爸现在不会在意...
About what I used to do .
关于我以前做过的事 。
In the end, Dad...
最后，爸爸...
I want to become an assistant.
我想成为一名助理。
Dad didn't care about us at all.
爸爸 根本不关心我们。
Kian.
基安.
You are becoming braver.
你正在变得更加勇敢。
OK. listen.
好的。听。
If my dad hadn't gotten an assistant job...
如果我爸爸没有找到一份助理工作...
My family...
我的家人...
Will I be able to live comfortably?
我能过上舒适的生活吗？
You and your brother...
你 和你弟弟...
Can you get whatever you want?
你能得到你想要的一切吗？
You have enjoyed all the benefits...
您已经享受了所有的好处...
And now you blame your father for ignoring you?
现在你却 责怪你的父亲不理你？
Who are you to do such a thing?
你是谁，竟敢做出这样的事？
to...
到...
Of course, you can't blame your father.
当然， 这也不能怪你的父亲。
But I really want to tell my dad...
但我真的很想告诉我爸爸...
My real feelings right now.
我现在的真实感受。
If you just want to do it...
如果你只是想做的话...
My family lives happily...
我的家人生活得很幸福...
Dad, will you listen to me?
爸爸， 你愿意听我说吗？
If you want to prove it...
如果你想证明这一点...
The Father's sacrifice was only for our good...
天父的牺牲 只是为了我们的利益......
I think it would be best for your father to resign.
我认为你父亲最好辞职。
The money I have...
我有的钱...
With our family wealth...
以我们家的财富...
Enough to open a small perfume shop...
足够开一家小香水店了...
In a small place...
在一个小地方...
Without worrying about food or accommodation...
不用担心吃饭和住宿...
All our lives.
我们一生。
That makes me happier than serving royalty...
这让我比为皇室服务更快乐......
Because we are afraid that our lives may be threatened .
因为我们害怕我们的生命可能受到威胁 。
Are you happier?
你更快乐吗？
You only think about your happiness .
你只考虑你的幸福 。
great.
伟大的。
If Dad resigns...
如果爸爸辞职了...
Who will protect your little brother...
谁来保护你的弟弟……
Can't you control it later?
以后就控制不住了吗？
Your father has allowed you to become the son-in-law of the head family...
你的父亲 让你成为了一家之主的女婿……
Because you can help him...
因为你可以帮助他...
If that person has a problem...
如果那个人有问题的话...
After we leave.
我们离开后。
But you only know how to act...
但你只知道如何行动...
Without thinking of others.
不考虑别人。
to...
到...
so...
所以...
I don't want to let go...
我不想放手...
Assistant position...
助理职位...
And my brother is just an excuse for my father.
而我的哥哥只是我父亲的一个借口。
nurse.
护士。
Dad knows this enviable job...
爸爸知道这份令人羡慕的工作...
Is that a big problem too?
这也是个大问题吗？
If dad could do anything...
如果爸爸能做点什么的话...
To remove a colleague for this position...
要删除担任此职位的同事...
They can do the same to Dad.
他们也 可以对爸爸做同样的事。
Later, when Dad leaves this place...
后来，当爸爸离开这个地方时……
Do you know what awaits our family?
你知道等待着我们一家人的是什么吗？
With prosperity comes loss .
繁荣伴随着损失 。
At that time , there was no one in my family...
那时 ，我家里没有人……
You might miss it.
你可能会错过它。
If Dad continues to be superstitious...
如果爸爸继续迷信的话...
With power and wealth...
有了权力和财富...
This will only make our family's situation worse...
这只会让我们家的处境变得更糟……
When the time comes.
在时机成熟时。
What does it mean?
这是什么意思？
Will this end badly for my family?
这会给我的家人带来不好的结局吗？
- honey! - father!
- 蜂蜜！ - 父亲！
- dad. - A rebellious child!
- 爸爸。 - 一个叛逆的孩子！
Honey, calm down!
亲爱的，冷静点！
After raising you for years ...
抚养你这么多年...
I only get disobedience from you!
我得到的只有你的不服从！
I really don't want to see you again.
我真的 不想再见到你。
Get out of here!
离开这里！
- now! - to!
- 现在！ - 到！
Honey, calm down!
亲爱的，冷静点！
Qian, that's it.
钱，就这样吧。
Kian. fast.
基安. 快速地。
Get your sister out of here.
带你妹妹离开这里。
It seems...
它似乎...
Unable to reach agreement...
无法达成一致...
Between us today.
今天我们之间。
If dad insists on being a helper...
如果爸爸 坚持要当帮手的话...
Please forgive me for disobeying you.
请原谅我不服从你。
This is just advice to fathers.
这只是给父亲们的建议。
Kian.
基安.
Please take good care of your sister.
请好好照顾你的妹妹。
Qian, come back and take care of yourself.
倩，回来照顾好自己。
- Kian. - Rest! I heard
- 基安。 - 休息！我听说
Don't come here again.
不要再来这里了。
Okay, honey.
好的亲爱的。
relax.
放松。
Kian.
基安.
You can't disobey your father.
你不能违背你的父亲。
Look how angry he is.
看他多生气。
What do you mean, go and apologize?
你什么意思，去道歉？
I think so too...
我也这么认为...
Did I do something wrong today?
我今天做错什么了吗？
I want to live...
我想生活...
With power and wealth...
有了权力和财富...
But it's full of fights...
但里面充满了打斗……
Or can you live peacefully in your village?
或者你能在你的村庄里平静地生活吗？
Why should we choose?
我们为什么要选择？
The Father is here, so what have we to fear?
天父就在这里， 我们还有什么好怕的呢？
Why should we live...
我们为什么要活...
In the Village?
在村里？
So, my brother is still used to being from a rich family...
所以说，哥哥 还是出身富贵人家习惯了……
And strength...
还有实力...
I don't want to be an ordinary person...
我不想当一个普通人...
And do you live a normal life?
你过着正常的生活吗？
Life is pretty good now.
现在生活已经很好了。
You worry too much.
你担心太多了。
Kediaman Hua
华克迪亚
obvious...
明显的...
No one in my family listens to me...
我家里没人 听我的...
Or trust me.
或者相信我。
let's go.
我们走吧。
Kian.
基安.
Tuan.
团。
Who did that?
谁干的？
Can I ask you a favor?
可以请你帮个忙吗？
There aren't many people who can hit me, right?
能打我的人不多吧？
You are still the Lady of the Bell Residence.
你还是钟府的夫人。
Don't let others bother you later.
以后别让别人打扰你。
If not, you are embarrassing me.
如果没有， 你就让我难堪了。
Do you care about me?
你在乎我吗？
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
I would like you to know something.
我想让你知道一些事情。
- you! - Can you see it now?
- 你！ - 你现在能看到吗？
If you force me to stay here ...
如果你强迫我留在这里 ...
I can't stand the pain in my eyes...
我无法忍受眼睛里的疼痛……
And it's impossible for me to live ...
而我，根本不可能活下去……
Be quiet here.
这里保持安静。
I'm just telling the truth.
我只是说实话。
Why did you hit me so hard?
你为什么这么狠心地打我？
Madam, is it true that you want a divorce?
女士， 您真的想离婚吗？
Are you divorced?
你离婚了？
I want to divorce, but it's not easy.
我想离婚，但这 并不容易。
In the end , if you decide to divorce...
最后 ，如果你决定离婚……
It will embarrass Tuan Yelan.
这会让团夜兰难堪。
He also said he would forget my mistake.
他还说 他会忘记我的错误。
I was just on the phone with my dad...
我刚刚和我爸爸通电话...
Look how I ended up like this .
看看我怎么就变成这样了。
Then ma'am...
那么夫人...
Why did you do that to Tuan Ye Lan earlier?
你刚才为什么要这样对团夜兰？
There is no way to ask for a divorce.
没有办法要求离婚。
So I have no choice but to force him.
所以我没有办法，只能强迫他。
This is it...
就是这个...
How is your research?
你的研究怎么样？
You don't want me to interfere.
你不想让我干涉。
But I haven't heard any news from you .
但我还没有听到你的任何消息 。
I came to tell you this.
我是来告诉你这个的。
My father just sent me a letter.
我父亲刚刚给我寄了一封信。
He discovered the perfume formula...
他发现了香水的配方......
Aquilaria scent can be made lower ...
沉香的香味可以降低 ...
Real scent.
真正的气味。
expert...
专家...
Based on decades of perfume experience
基于数十年的 香水经验
Can't tell the difference.
无法区分。
So my father was deceived.
于是我父亲就被骗了。
This technology...
这项技术...
It's the same technology...
都是一样的技术...
This is what the Ge family uses.
葛家就是用的这个。
After listening to the conversation...
听完对话后...
Between you and the owner that day ...
那天你和主人 之间...
I got a clue.
我得到了线索。
What you mean is...
你的意思是...
Were the runaway Ge family also involved in the same thing?
难道逃亡的葛家也 卷入了同样的事情？
So why did they imprison your family?
那么 他们为什么要监禁你的家人呢？
I don't know
我不知道
But there's something strange about the man in the middle...
但中间的那个人却有些奇怪……
A person who delivered furniture...
一个送家具的人...
Including...
包括...
To our accommodation.
到我们的住宿地。
After the family was arrested and imprisoned...
一家人被捕 入狱后……
He just disappeared.
他就这样消失了。
Whether alive or dead, no one can find him.
无论生死，没有人能找到他。
Recently I talked to Hua Qian prostitutes.
最近我 和花千妓聊过。
This issue is very complex.
这个问题非常复杂。
That person may not be the main character...
那个人可能不是主角……
But he could also be an accomplice.
但他也可能是同谋。
But the Fahrenheit family might be hostile...
但飞轮海家族 可能会怀有敌意……
With the Ge family.
与葛家。
So have you ever thought about it...
那么你有没有想过...
Maybe Hua Qian happened to...
也许华谦碰巧……
Suggest you a bad broker...
给你推荐一个不好的经纪人...
Does he have anything to do with this?
他和这件事有什么关系吗？
You've never seen him...
你从未见过他...
Deny this...
否认这个...
Or just look at how he rejects me...
或者 看看他是如何拒绝我的...
When I asked him the truth.
当我问他真相时。
So I understand why you think that.
所以我 理解你为什么这么想。
I didn't mean it that way.
我不是那个意思。
It's very difficult for me to research.
对我来说研究起来非常困难。
If you can't stand it...
如果你受不了的话...
And I don't want to continue...
而且我不想继续了...
I will not force you to help me.
我不会强迫你帮助我。
no.
不。
Because this case is unfair...
因为这个案子不公平……
We need to investigate the truth.
我们需要调查真相。
If you need help, you can instruct Nanfeng.
如果需要帮助，可以指点南风。
Hua Qian 풀라...
Hua Qian 풀라...
Madam, Madam Hua sent another letter.
夫人， 华夫人又来信了。
Set it aside.
把它放在一边。
approval.
赞同。
ma'am.
女士。
It's been a few days ma'am. Mr. Hua wrote a letter to her wife.
已经好几天了， 女士。华先生给妻子写了一封信。
Read it first.
首先阅读它。
He wants me back...
他要我回来...
And I apologize to my father.
我向我的父亲道歉。
So it's okay if you don't read it.
所以不读也没关系。
Are you not going to talk to that person again ?
你不再和那个人说话了吗 ？
Of course not.
当然不是。
I just want them to know where I am.
我只是 想让他们知道我在哪里。
Although their views cannot be changed immediately ...
虽然他们的看法不能立即改变 ……
It will affect them.
这会影响他们。
Cik puan, Nanfeng datang.
Cik puan, Nanfeng datang.
Why did he come again?
他怎么又来了？
What's the problem this time?
这次出了什么问题？
Let him in.
让他进来。
Hello, madam.
你好女士。
What is that?
那是什么？
Are you having trouble at home?
你家里有麻烦吗？
no.
不。
I came to talk to the lady ...
我是来跟那位女士说话的 ……
The feast will be held three days later...
三天后，宴会将举行……
And you want your wife to attend with him...
而且你 想让你的妻子和他一起参加......
Di Taman species.
迪塔曼种。
Who will be there?
谁会在那里？
Directors gathered from all over the country...
来自全国各地的导演齐聚一堂...
Wu family and other suppliers...
吴氏家族等供应商...
A person who worked with the Zhong family.
与钟家共事的人。
Keluar woo?
Keluar woo？
Will that happen in the end?
最终会发生这种情况吗？
Do you have any questions?
你有任何问题吗？
Why do you want me to attend?
为什么要我参加？
It's a big party.
这是一个大聚会。
Of course, you must also attend.
当然， 你也必须参加。
Lakaman Bonus
拉卡曼奖金
you?
你？
Did you come back after so many years ?
这么多年 你回来了吗？
I want you to make me something.
我要你给我做点东西。
Just curious...
只是好奇...
Why did you come to see me?
你为什么来看我？
Looks...
看起来...
you want something from me
你想从我这里得到一些东西
Any price is acceptable.
任何价格都是可以接受的。
Why do you talk like we are foreigners?
为什么你说话就像我们是外国人一样？
After all, I have been your teacher for several years.
毕竟，我 已经当你的老师好几年了。
Are you really a good apprentice?
你真的是个好徒弟吗？